<bibdata type="standard">
  <fetched>2019-08-03</fetched>
  <title type="title-main" format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">Standard representation of geographic point location by coordinates</title>
  <title type="main" format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">Standard representation of geographic point location by coordinates</title>
  <title type="title-main" format="text/plain" language="fr" script="Latn">Représentation normalisée de la localisation des points géographiques par coordonnées</title>
  <title type="main" format="text/plain" language="fr" script="Latn">Représentation normalisée de la localisation des points géographiques par coordonnées</title>
  <uri type="src">https://www.iso.org/standard/39242.html</uri>
  <uri type="obp">https://www.iso.org/obp/ui/#!iso:std:39242:en</uri>
  <uri type="rss">https://www.iso.org/contents/data/standard/03/92/39242.detail.rss</uri>
  <docidentifier type="ISO">ISO 6709:2008</docidentifier>
  <date type="published">
    <on>2008</on>
  </date>
  <contributor>
    <role type="publisher"/>
    <organization>
      <name>International Organization for Standardization</name>
      <abbreviation>ISO</abbreviation>
      <uri>www.iso.org</uri>
    </organization>
  </contributor>
  <edition>2</edition>
  <language>en</language>
  <language>fr</language>
  <script>Latn</script>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">ISO 6709:2008 is applicable to the interchange of coordinates describing geographic point location. It specifies the representation of coordinates, including latitude and longitude, to be used in data interchange. It additionally specifies representation of horizontal point location using coordinate types other than latitude and longitude. It also specifies the representation of height and depth that can be associated with horizontal coordinates. Representation includes units of measure and coordinate order.ISO 6709:2008 is not applicable to the representation of information held within computer memories during processing and in their use in registers of geodetic codes and parameters.ISO 6709:2008 supports point location representation through the eXtensible Markup Language (XML) and, recognizing the need for compatibility with the previous version of this International Standard, ISO 6709:1983, allows for the use of a single alpha-numeric string to describe point locations.For computer data interchange of latitude and longitude, ISO 6709:2008 generally suggests that decimal degrees be used. It allows the use of sexagesimal notations: degrees, minutes and decimal minutes or degrees, minutes, seconds and decimal seconds.ISO 6709:2008 does not require special internal procedures, file-organization techniques, storage medium, languages, etc., to be used in its implementation.</abstract>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="fr" script="Latn">L'ISO 6709:2008 est applicable à l'échange des coordonnées décrivant la localisation de points géographiques. Elle spécifie la représentation des coordonnées, dont la latitude et la longitude, utilisées pour l'échange de données. En outre, elle spécifie la représentation de la localisation des points horizontaux en utilisant les types de coordonnées différents de la latitude et de la longitude. Elle spécifie aussi la représentation de la hauteur et de la profondeur qui peuvent être associées à des coordonnées horizontales. La représentation inclut l'ordre des unités de mesure et des coordonnées.L'ISO 6709:2008 n'est pas applicable à la représentation des informations gardées dans les mémoires des ordinateurs pendant leur traitement et leur utilisation dans les enregistrements des codes et des paramètres géodésiques.L'ISO 6709:2008 supporte la représentation de la localisation des points au moyen de XML (langage de balisage extensible) et, par respect de la nécessité de compatibilité avec l'édition précédente, l'ISO 6709:1983, elle permet l'utilisation d'une chaîne alphanumérique unique pour décrire la localisation des points.Pour l'échange des données informatisées sur la latitude et la longitude, l'ISO 6709:2008 suggère généralement d'utiliser les fractions décimales de degrés. Elle permet l'utilisation des notations sexagésimales: les degrés, les minutes et les fractions décimales de minutes ou les degrés, les minutes, les secondes et les fractions décimales de secondes.L'ISO 6709:2008 ne comporte pas d'exigences spécifiques concernant les procédures internes, les techniques d'organisation des fichiers, les moyens de sauvegarde, les langages, etc. pour sa mise en oeuvre.</abstract>
  <status>
    <stage>90</stage>
    <substage>92</substage>
  </status>
  <copyright>
    <from>2008</from>
    <owner>
      <organization>
        <name>ISO</name>
      </organization>
    </owner>
  </copyright>
  <relation type="obsoletes">
    <bibitem type="standard">
      <formattedref format="text/plain">ISO 6709:1983</formattedref>
    </bibitem>
  </relation>
  <relation type="updates">
    <bibitem type="standard">
      <formattedref format="text/plain">ISO 6709:2008/Cor 1:2009</formattedref>
    </bibitem>
  </relation>
  <relation type="obsoletes">
    <bibitem type="standard">
      <formattedref format="text/plain">ISO/NP 6709</formattedref>
    </bibitem>
  </relation>
  <ext>
    <doctype>international-standard</doctype>
    <editorialgroup>
      <technical_committee number="211" type="TC">ISO/TC 211Geographic information/Geomatics</technical_committee>
    </editorialgroup>
    <ics>
      <code>35.240.70</code>
      <text>IT applications in science</text>
    </ics>
    <structuredidentifier type="ISO">
      <project-number>ISO 6709</project-number>
    </structuredidentifier>
  </ext>
</bibdata>