<bibdata type="standard">
  <fetched>2019-08-03</fetched>
  <title type="title-main" format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">Addressing</title>
  <title type="title-part" format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">Part 1: Conceptual model</title>
  <title type="main" format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">Addressing - Part 1: Conceptual model</title>
  <title type="title-main" format="text/plain" language="fr" script="Latn">Adressage</title>
  <title type="title-part" format="text/plain" language="fr" script="Latn">Partie 1: Modèle conceptuel</title>
  <title type="main" format="text/plain" language="fr" script="Latn">Adressage - Partie 1: Modèle conceptuel</title>
  <uri type="src">https://www.iso.org/standard/61710.html</uri>
  <uri type="obp">https://www.iso.org/obp/ui/#!iso:std:61710:en</uri>
  <uri type="rss">https://www.iso.org/contents/data/standard/06/17/61710.detail.rss</uri>
  <docidentifier type="ISO">ISO 19160-1:2015</docidentifier>
  <date type="published">
    <on>2015</on>
  </date>
  <contributor>
    <role type="publisher"/>
    <organization>
      <name>International Organization for Standardization</name>
      <abbreviation>ISO</abbreviation>
      <uri>www.iso.org</uri>
    </organization>
  </contributor>
  <edition>1</edition>
  <language>en</language>
  <language>fr</language>
  <script>Latn</script>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">ISO 19160-1:2015 defines a conceptual model for address information (address model), together with the terms and definitions that describe the concepts in the model. Lifecycle, metadata, and address aliases are included in the conceptual model. The model is presented in the Unified Modeling Language (UML).The model provides a common representation of address information, independent of actual addressing implementations. It is not intended to replace conceptual models proposed in other specifications, but provides a means to cross-map between different conceptual models for address information and enables the conversion of address information between specifications.The model provides a basis for developing address specifications by individual countries or communities.</abstract>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="fr" script="Latn">L'ISO 19160-1:2015 définit un modèle conceptuel pour les informations d'adresse (modèle d'adresse), ainsi que les termes et définitions décrivant les concepts qui lui sont associés. Le modèle conceptuel comprend le cycle de vie, les métadonnées et les alias d'adresse. Il est présenté en langage de modélisation unifié (UML).Le modèle offre une représentation commune des informations d'adresse, indépendamment des mises en ?uvre réelles de l'adressage. Il n'a pas vocation à remplacer les modèles conceptuels proposés dans d'autres spécifications, mais offre plutôt un moyen d'établir une correspondance entre différents modèles conceptuels régissant les informations d'adresse tout en facilitant la conversion des informations d'adresse d'une spécification à une autre.Le modèle offre une base pour l'élaboration de spécifications d'adresses dans différents pays ou communautés.</abstract>
  <status>
    <stage>60</stage>
    <substage>60</substage>
  </status>
  <copyright>
    <from>2015</from>
    <owner>
      <organization>
        <name>ISO</name>
      </organization>
    </owner>
  </copyright>
  <ext>
    <doctype>international-standard</doctype>
    <editorialgroup>
      <technical_committee number="211" type="TC">ISO/TC 211Geographic information/Geomatics</technical_committee>
    </editorialgroup>
    <ics>
      <code>35.240.70</code>
      <text>IT applications in science</text>
    </ics>
    <structuredidentifier type="ISO">
      <project-number>ISO 19160</project-number>
    </structuredidentifier>
  </ext>
</bibdata>