<bibdata type="standard">
  <fetched>2019-07-04</fetched>
  <title type="title-main" format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">Imagery sensor models for geopositioning</title>
  <title type="title-intro" format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">Geographic information</title>
  <title type="title-part" format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">Part 2: SAR, InSAR, lidar and sonar</title>
  <title type="main" format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">Imagery sensor models for geopositioning - Geographic information - Part 2: SAR, InSAR, lidar and sonar</title>
  <title type="title-main" format="text/plain" language="fr" script="Latn">Modèles de capteurs d'images de géopositionnement</title>
  <title type="title-intro" format="text/plain" language="fr" script="Latn">Information géographique</title>
  <title type="title-part" format="text/plain" language="fr" script="Latn">Partie 2: SAR, InSAR, lidar et sonar</title>
  <title type="main" format="text/plain" language="fr" script="Latn">Modèles de capteurs d'images de géopositionnement - Information géographique - Partie 2: SAR, InSAR, lidar et sonar</title>
  <uri type="src">https://www.iso.org/standard/56113.html</uri>
  <uri type="obp">https://www.iso.org/obp/ui/#!iso:std:56113:en</uri>
  <uri type="rss">https://www.iso.org/contents/data/standard/05/61/56113.detail.rss</uri>
  <docidentifier type="ISO">ISO/TS 19130-2:2014</docidentifier>
  <date type="published">
    <on>2014</on>
  </date>
  <contributor>
    <role type="publisher"/>
    <organization>
      <name>International Organization for Standardization</name>
      <abbreviation>ISO</abbreviation>
      <uri>www.iso.org</uri>
    </organization>
  </contributor>
  <contributor>
    <role type="publisher"/>
    <organization>
      <name>International Organization for Standardization</name>
      <abbreviation>TS</abbreviation>
      <uri>www.iso.org</uri>
    </organization>
  </contributor>
  <edition>1</edition>
  <language>en</language>
  <language>fr</language>
  <script>Latn</script>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">ISO/TS 19130-2:2014 supports exploitation of remotely sensed images. It specifies the sensor models and metadata for geopositioning images remotely sensed by Synthetic Aperture Radar (SAR), Interferometric Synthetic Aperture Radar (InSAR), LIght Detection And Ranging (lidar), and SOund Navigation And Ranging (sonar) sensors. The specification also defines the metadata needed for the aerial triangulation of airborne and spaceborne images.ISO/TS 19130-2:2014 specifies the detailed information that shall be provided for a sensor description of SAR, InSAR, lidar, and sonar sensors with the associated physical and geometric information necessary to rigorously construct a physical sensor model. For the case where precise geoposition information is needed, this Technical Specification identifies the mathematical formulae for rigorously constructing physical sensor models that relate two-dimensional image space to three-dimensional ground space and the calculation of the associated propagated error.ISO/TS 19130-2:2014 does not specify either how users derive geoposition data or the format or content of the data the users generate.</abstract>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="fr" script="Latn">L'ISO/TS 19130-2:2014 prend en charge l'exploitation des images de télédétection. Elle spécifie les modèles de capteurs et les métadonnées pour la géolocalisation des images de télédétection des capteurs radar à synthèse d'ouverture (SAR), radar interférométrique à synthèse d'ouverture (Interferometric Synthetic Aperture Radar - InSAR), télédétection par laser (lidar) et sonar. Elle définit également les métadonnées nécessaires à l'aérotriangulation des images aéroportées et spatioportées.L'ISO/TS 19130-2:2014 donne les informations détaillées qui doivent être fournies pour la description des capteurs de SAR, InSAR, lidar et sonar, ainsi que les informations physiques et géométriques associées nécessaires à la construction rigoureuse d'un modèle physique de capteur. Pour les cas où des informations de géolocalisation précises sont nécessaires, la présente Spécification technique identifie les formules mathématiques permettant la construction rigoureuse de modèles physiques de capteurs qui mettent en relation l'espace-image en deux dimensions et l'espace-sol en trois dimensions en intégrant le calcul de l'erreur de propagation associée.L'ISO/TS 19130-2:2014 ne précise ni comment les utilisateurs dérivent les données de géolocalisation, ni le format ou le contenu des données qu'ils génèrent.</abstract>
  <status>
    <stage>90</stage>
    <substage>93</substage>
  </status>
  <copyright>
    <from>2014</from>
    <owner>
      <organization>
        <name>ISO/TS</name>
      </organization>
    </owner>
  </copyright>
  <ext>
    <doctype>technical-specification</doctype>
    <editorialgroup>
      <technical_committee number="211" type="TC">ISO/TC 211Geographic information/Geomatics</technical_committee>
    </editorialgroup>
    <ics>
      <code>35.240.70</code>
      <text>IT applications in science</text>
    </ics>
    <structuredidentifier type="ISO">
      <project-number>ISO/TS 19130</project-number>
    </structuredidentifier>
  </ext>
</bibdata>