<bibdata type="standard">
  <fetched>2019-07-04</fetched>
  <title type="title-main" format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">Basic and general concepts and associated terms (VIM)</title>
  <title type="title-intro" format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">International vocabulary of metrology</title>
  <title type="main" format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">Basic and general concepts and associated terms (VIM) - International vocabulary of metrology</title>
  <title type="title-main" format="text/plain" language="fr" script="Latn">Concepts fondamentaux et généraux et termes associés (VIM)</title>
  <title type="title-intro" format="text/plain" language="fr" script="Latn">Vocabulaire international de métrologie</title>
  <title type="main" format="text/plain" language="fr" script="Latn">Concepts fondamentaux et généraux et termes associés (VIM) - Vocabulaire international de métrologie</title>
  <uri type="src">https://www.iso.org/standard/45324.html</uri>
  <uri type="obp">https://www.iso.org/obp/ui/#!iso:std:45324:en</uri>
  <uri type="rss">https://www.iso.org/contents/data/standard/04/53/45324.detail.rss</uri>
  <docidentifier type="ISO">ISO/IEC Guide 99:2007</docidentifier>
  <date type="published">
    <on>2007</on>
  </date>
  <contributor>
    <role type="publisher"/>
    <organization>
      <name>International Organization for Standardization</name>
      <abbreviation>ISO</abbreviation>
      <uri>www.iso.org</uri>
    </organization>
  </contributor>
  <contributor>
    <role type="publisher"/>
    <organization>
      <name>International Electrotechnical Commission</name>
      <abbreviation>IEC</abbreviation>
      <uri>www.iec.ch</uri>
    </organization>
  </contributor>
  <edition>1</edition>
  <language>en</language>
  <language>fr</language>
  <script>Latn</script>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">ISO/IEC Guide 99:2007 provides a set of definitions and associated terms, in English and French, for a system of basic and general concepts used in metrology, together with concept diagrams to demonstrate their relations. Additional information is given in the form of examples and notes under many definitions.This Vocabulary is meant to be a common reference for scientists and engineers, as well as teachers and practitioners, involved in planning or performing measurements, irrespective of the level of measurement uncertainty and irrespective of the field of application. It is also meant to be a reference for governmental and inter-governmental bodies, trade associations, accredi­tation bodies, regulators and professional societies.</abstract>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="fr" script="Latn">Le Guide ISO/CEI 99:2007 donne un ensemble de définitions et de termes associés, en anglais et en français, pour un système de concepts fondamentaux et généraux utilisés en métrologie, ainsi que des schémas conceptuels illustrant leurs relations. Pour un grand nombre de définitions, des informations complémentaires sont données sous forme d'exemples et de notes.Le Guide ISO/CEI 99:2007 se propose d'être une référence commune pour les scientifiques et les ingénieurs, ainsi que les enseignants et les praticiens, impliqués dans la planification ou la réalisation de mesurages, quels que soient le domaine d'application et le niveau d'incertitude de mesure. Il se propose aussi d'être une référence pour les organismes gouvernementaux et intergouvernementaux, les associations commerciales, les comités d'accréditation, les régulateurs et les associations professionnelles.</abstract>
  <status>
    <stage>90</stage>
    <substage>93</substage>
  </status>
  <copyright>
    <from>2007</from>
    <owner>
      <organization>
        <name>ISO/IEC</name>
      </organization>
    </owner>
  </copyright>
  <relation type="obsoletes">
    <bibitem type="standard">
      <formattedref format="text/plain">ISO Guide 99:1993</formattedref>
    </bibitem>
  </relation>
  <ext>
    <doctype>guide</doctype>
    <editorialgroup>
      <technical_committee type="TC">ISO/TMBGTechnical Management Board - groups</technical_committee>
    </editorialgroup>
    <ics>
      <code>17.020</code>
      <text>Metrology and measurement in general</text>
    </ics>
    <ics>
      <code>01.040.17</code>
      <text>Metrology and measurement. Physical phenomena (Vocabularies)</text>
    </ics>
    <structuredidentifier type="ISO">
      <project-number>ISO/IEC Guide 99</project-number>
    </structuredidentifier>
  </ext>
</bibdata>